<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: tech | blog.jbinto.ca]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.jbinto.ca//blog/categories/tech/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.jbinto.ca//"/>
  <updated>2012-10-27T19:04:08-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.jbinto.ca//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jesse (jbinto)]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First impressions of Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.jbinto.ca//blog/2012/10/27/first-impressions-of-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-27T14:35:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.jbinto.ca//blog/2012/10/27/first-impressions-of-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It's interesting. It shows I still have a lot to learn. I don't need to know how
everything works exactly: I can treat it as a black box and still be productive.
But here's some things I need to work on:</p>

<ul>
<li>CSS 3 including media queries, responsive design</li>
<li>Markdown: I know how to make links and lists, but that's about it.</li>
<li>Sass: A CSS compiler to make things <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don't_repeat_yourself">DRY</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>How I updated the CSS</h2>

<p>I've never been very good at CSS. CSS3 with Sass is almost completely foreign to
me. Since responsive design is all the rage these days, I'll resist my
temptation to rip it all out and start from scratch, and gradually obtain an
understanding of it over time. In the meantime, the Sass is structured in a way
that lets you set customizations (colors, fonts) in a centralized place.</p>

<p>I'm just poking around at these values. <code>desaturate</code> and <code>lighten</code> are
Sass functions.</p>

<p><code>css sass/_custom/_colors.scss
$header-bg: #0f164b;
$nav-bg: desaturate(lighten(#80849f, 18), 5);
$sidebar-bg: desaturate(#eceff5, 8);
</code></p>

<p>``` css sass/<em>custom/</em>styles.scss</p>

<h1>content {</h1>

<p>   font-size: 87.5%;
}</p>

<p>header {
  font-size: 68%;
  text-decoration: underline;
}</p>

<p>h2 {
  color: #93A1A1;
}</p>

<p>/<em> The nav seems like a waste of space to me. </em>/
nav { display: none; }</p>

<p>/<em> Everything is too big... </em>/
pre { font-size: 75%; }
```</p>

<h2>Things I still don't like</h2>

<ul>
<li><p>Heroku has an almost 10 second spin-up time when your app has been inactive.
I may move it elsewhere.</p></li>
<li><p>I don't know what to do about images. If I move to a static host, I could just
host them myself. I've tried <a href="http://500px.com/">500px</a> and honestly don't care
for it.</p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Working with a static blog generator]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.jbinto.ca//blog/2012/10/25/working-with-a-static-blog-generator/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-25T20:42:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.jbinto.ca//blog/2012/10/25/working-with-a-static-blog-generator</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am using <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a>. This is a little different from other blog software.
Rather than being generated on the fly, and dependent on a database and application code, this
is a "static blog". I write and manage actual "post" files, and I run a command to generate the
HTML, CSS, the whole site. It's also a <a href="http://git-scm.com/">Git</a> repository, so I have the whole thing under source
control. And since it's a Git repository, I can push it to <a href="http://www.heroku.com/">Heroku</a>, which is hosting this content.</p>

<p>It will take some getting used to, but it's a neat approach. It is absolutely more secure than a typical
Wordpress installation. It can be hosted for free or nearly free almost anywhere, since it's just static HTML.
It will be lightning fast, since it's just static HTML.</p>

<p>It's also an extreme approach: SSH keys, git repos... if I wasn't already well-versed in this, I would probably be frustrated.</p>

<p>Things I'm not so sure how to do, and should find out:</p>

<ul>
<li>Edit the CSS and make it feel different. It uses <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Responsive_web_design">responsive design</a>, which I'm not sure I'll comprehend right away.</li>
<li>How to embed images (where should they be hosted?)</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
